Speaking workshop tips
	debunk
		"I have nothing to talk about"
			Your point of view and your way of expressing it is unique.
			 about anything you know to any audience that doesn’t already know it.
			You can also talk about something brand new for you. It doesn’t matter if you don’t know anything about the topic yet, either, since I promise you will know a lot about it when you give the talk. Giving a talk is a fantastic way to learn. Give the talk you want to hear.
		“I’d be a terrible speaker”
			You need only two things to be a great speaker: practice and confidence. The fastest route to confidence is practice, so really you just need practice. Practice means: rehearsing your talk a few times before giving it, but also giving more talks to get better at preparing them.
			start small
		“I’m afraid of public speaking”
			Most of us are intimidated by public speaking. I’m afraid every single time, but then, because I’m prepared and I’ve practiced, everything goes well and I end up feeling great.
		“I’m not nearly as nerdy and intense as some of those guys I’ve seen give talks”
			Those guys don’t represent programmers in general, and you should not compare yourself with them. Be you. That’s the whole point of having diverse people participate; for diverse viewpoints.
		“But I’m not ready yet!”
			All you need to prepare and submit is a talk proposal. Spend an evening sketching out an idea, and write up a paragraph describing the theme. If your proposal is accepted, then you can get to work on getting the talk prepared.
		don't be afraid to repeat your talk
		I don’t see myself as a developer-y enough developer to warrant giving a talk on developing
			speaking is one of the best way to solidify what you have learned, along with spreading it to others.
		I’m not an expert, why would anybody want to listen to me?
		I’m going to sound stupid.
		What if I mess up?
		I don’t have anything interesting to say.
		Just tell yourself that this is the result of fear of a new situation. Then tell yourself there are no lions waiting out there to eat you and that you can do this.
	preparing a talk
		start with a sentence
		write the abstract
			4-6 sentences. Background and introduction. Problem statement/thesis. What can the audience expect to takeaway from the talk?
		write the outline
		make a slide outline
		presentation software
		run throughs
			at least a couple
		Raise your profile by producing blog content that means something to you and will also provide value to your readers
			Writing about your work or side projects can give you material for talks, so it’s less of a strain to come up with a topic. It also gives your name credibility if that content starts to make the rounds on social media and industry newsletters.
		Do your homework
			Picking the right event
				Submit to local events first to gain experience and exposure. … You can also benefit at any point in your speaking career by practicing talks at local meetups before taking them to larger conferences.
			Research on the event
				A winning proposal will identify how your topic fits in with the overall conference agenda, highlighting who stands to benefit from learning from you; and, what they’ll get out of it.
			Becoming a part of the community
				By experiencing an event before you submit a talk, you can also potentially network with the very people who will approve your proposal.
				It helps to attend conferences if you want to speak at said conferences
		Have a clear reason for giving the talk
		Know your ideas, not the exact words
		Stay on topic
		Types
			The Case Study
			The Deep Dive
			The Overview
			The “Let Me Show You”
		practice, again and again
			When you know a presentation and are confident in giving it you become freer to improvise, to play to the crowd, to react to the room. Your mind is no longer concerned with messing it up, its free to improvise and be creative.
			Rehearse
		Slides
			Make it readable
			Avoid bullets
			Use code carefully
			Shape first, design later
			Invest time or money into images
		their feedback is critical to my process
	submitting a talk
		don’t rely on reputation
		tell what you’re going to SAY
		provide links to your stuff, if you want them to look at it
		check the detail, make it polished
		the title draws people to the talk
		You don’t have to know everything about the topic when you write the abstract; in fact, you should leave some mystery for the talk itself! You have time to research and fill in the details after you submit the abstract.
		Ask for feedback on your proposals
		Starting with (almost) nothing
			It’s common
			It’s a great way to motivate yourself
			It’s a great way to learn
			But warning: It can be a lot of work
			Learning from rejection
		Direct the proposal to the attendees, not the curators
		Be specific about the focus your talk will have
			Generally speaking, a shallow introduction to many things is not as interesting as an in-depth introduction to one thing.
		Make your point as succinctly as you can
		Have your proposal reviewed by someone with experience
		Always follow outlined Call for Speakers rules
		Ask friends to proof-read
		Be succinct
		Use inclusive language and avoid shaming
		Stay away from product pitches
		Show, don’t tell
		Submit more than one proposal
		Imagine who will be at the conference
		Imagine the decision to see your talk
		Capture that excitement in your proposal
		Tell a story
		Don’t bury the lead
		Seal the deal in the description
		Pick a topic you feel passionate about and research what topics the conference might be interested in.
		Good bio
		Set the right goal.
		Show them you’ve been there.
		pick a relevant topic to discuss
		tell organizers what you're going to discuss with some detail.
		Awesome bio
		Specify the audience and the takeaways.
		Put the important facts first.
	giving a talk
		Your content is conference value. Don’t feel ashamed of asking conferences to pay.
		When someone compliments your talk, say thank you, don’t argue. Engage them.
		Never apologize at the beginning of a talk.
		Long introductions mean you can get less content in. Tighten them up to almost nothing.
		You run long. Write your talks to be shorter than the window.
		Be an accessible, persuasive speaker
			Public speakers should leave the audience feeling good. The purpose of getting up in front of a conference (usually) is to spread awareness about a new technology or initiative, teach people something, and entertain them. As an audience member, I value when speakers are approachable and bring me along, rather than making me feel bad because I’m not on their level yet. If they show a bit of vulnerability by saying how they failed before getting it right, even better.
		Upload your slides in advance so the audience can follow along.
		Arrive early to your talk room
		Have backups everywhere (Google Drive, Dropbox, iCloud)
		Take off your badge before you begin
		Co-presenting
		Combating nervousness
			the nervousness is designed to warn you of potential danger, but there’s no real danger. You can thank your body for the consideration and calmly say, “I got this.”
		Tell a story
		Be enthusiastic
		Don’t try to be funny
		Be yourself
		Speak slowly
