Speaking workshop
	Debunking myths
		"I have nothing to talk about"
			Your point of view is unique.
			Your way of expressing it is unique.
			Talk about something brand new for you.
				Giving a talk is a fantastic way to learn.
				But warning: It can be a lot of work
		“I’d be a terrible speaker”
			Gain confidence.
				Practice
			Practice.
				Rehearse a few times.
				Give more talks to get better at preparing them.
			Start small
		“I’m afraid of public speaking”
			Most of us are! Practice. Things goes well, you end up feeling great.
			Just fear of a new situation.
				You can do this.
		“I’m not nearly as nerdy and intense as some of those people I’ve seen give talks” / “I’m not an expert”
			Don’t compare yourself with them. Be you. We need diverse viewpoints.
			What doesn’t the audience already know?
		“But I’m not ready yet!”
			Submit a proposal
				If it’s accepted, work on the talk.
			You don’t have to know everything about the topic when you write the abstract
		Don't be afraid to repeat your talk
		“I’m not a developer-y enough”
			Speaking solidifies what you have learned.
			Speaking spreads it to others.
	Preparing a talk
		Make a slide outline
		Stay on topic
		Practice
			Again and again!
			Knowing it gives you confidence, room to improvise.
		Slides
			Shape first, design later
			Make it readable
			Avoid bullets
			Use code carefully
			Invest time or money into images
		Get regular feedback
		You run long. Write your talks to be shorter than the window.
		Know your ideas, not the exact words
		Hard a short introduction to get more content in.
	Preparation
		Picking the right event
			Local meetups good for first steps
			Larger conferences good for later
		Research on the event
			Overall event agenda
		Becoming a part of the community
			Attend the event
			Network
		Blog about your work or side projects
			Raise your profile
			Means something to you
			Value to your readers
			Gives you credibility
	Giving a talk
		Before the talk
			Have backups everywhere (Google Drive, Dropbox, iCloud)
			Upload your slides in advance so the audience can follow along.
			Arrive early to your talk room
			Take off your badge before you begin
			Nervousness is designed to warn you of potential danger. Thank your body for the consideration and calmly say, “I got this.”
		During the talk
			Be an accessible, persuasive speaker
				Leave the audience feeling good. Bring them along.
				Show a bit of vulnerability by saying how you failed before getting it right.
			Never apologize at the beginning of a talk.
			Show, don’t tell
			Speak slowly
			Be yourself
			Don’t try to be funny
			Tell a story
			Be enthusiastic
		After the talk
			When someone compliments your talk, say thank you, don’t argue. Engage them.
	Submitting a talk
		Start with the title
			Draw people in
		The audience
			Who will be there?
			How will people decide to see your talk?
			Say what you're going to discuss in detail.
			Specify the audience.
		Some types
			The Case Study
			The Deep Dive
			The Overview
			The “Let Me Show You”
		The abstract
			Background and introduction.
			Problem statement/thesis.
			Be succinct
			Be specific
			Put the important facts first.
			Capture your excitement and passion about the topic in your proposal
			Specify the takeaways.
			Use inclusive language and avoid shaming
			Stay away from product pitches
			Show them you’ve been there.
			Check the detail, make it polished
		Good bio
			Provide links to your stuff, if you want them to look at it
		Have your proposal reviewed
			Ask friends
			Someone with experience
			Ask for feedback on your proposals
		Submit more than one proposal
