Speaking workshop
	Debunking myths
		"I have nothing to talk about"
			Your point of view is unique.
			Talk about something brand new for you.
				Giving a talk is a fantastic way to learn.
				But warning: It can be a lot of work
		“I’d be a terrible speaker”
			Your way of expressing things is unique.
			Gain confidence.
				Practice
			Practice.
				Rehearse a few times.
				Give more talks to get better at preparing them.
			Start small
		“I’m afraid of public speaking”
			Most of us are!
				Practice helps.
			It’s okay to be nervous
				It’s because you care.
		“I’m not nearly as nerdy and intense as some of those people I’ve seen give talks” / “I’m not an expert”
			Don’t compare yourself with them. Be you. We need diverse viewpoints.
			What doesn’t the audience already know?
			You have expertise.
				Speaking solidifies what you have learned.
				Speaking spreads it to others.
		“But I’m not ready yet!”
			Submit a proposal
				If it’s accepted, work on the talk.
			You don’t have to know everything about the topic when you write the abstract
		Don't be afraid to repeat your talk
		“I’m not a developer-y enough”
		“There are unbreakable, must-do, rules for speaking.”
			Nope. Be yourself.
		“I’ll get it wrong / what if someone knows more than me?”
			Get comfortable with “I don’t know.” :)
	Preparing a talk
		Make a slide outline
		Shape
			Get regular feedback
			You run long. Write your talks to be shorter than the window.
			Know your ideas, not the exact words
			Have a short introduction to get more content in.
			Challenge stereotypes and combat biases (yours and theirs)
			What are the next steps (after the talk) for the audience?
		Slides
			Shape first, design later
			Make it readable
			Avoid bullets
			Use code carefully
			Invest time or money into images
			Presenter notes
			Stay on topic
		Practice
			Again and again!
			Knowing it gives you confidence, room to improvise.
			Your words
			Your technical set-up
			Timing
			If you make a mistake, acknowledge it and keep going.
			Get good feedback
				Tell them what kind you want, on what
				Give them context for the talk
				Ask for specific, actionable feedback
	Preparation
		Picking the right event
			Lunch and learn
			Local meetups (good for first steps)
			Conferences
		Research on the event
			Overall event agenda
		Becoming a part of the community
			Attend the event
			Network
		Blog about your work or side projects
			Raise your profile
			Means something to you
			Value to your readers
			Gives you credibility
			Good for testing an idea
		Which facet are you inspecting / lens are you bringing?
			“Intro to X” are always popular
			What was the hardest part of the project?
			What mistakes do the team make? What did you learn from them?
			Code, tool, process, workflow?
	Giving a talk
		Before the talk
			Have backups everywhere (Google Drive, Dropbox, iCloud)
			Upload your slides in advance so the audience can follow along.
			Arrive early to your talk room
			Take off your badge before you begin
			Nervousness is designed to warn you of potential danger. Thank your body for the consideration and calmly say, “I got this.”
		During the talk
			Be an accessible, persuasive speaker
				Leave the audience feeling good. Bring them along.
				Show a bit of vulnerability by saying how you failed before getting it right.
			Never apologize at the beginning of a talk.
			Speak slowly
			Be yourself
			Don’t try to be funny
			Tell a story
			Be enthusiastic
			Set expectations. Use an agenda or overview
			Make it interactive: ask questions
		After the talk
			When someone compliments your talk, say thank you, don’t argue. Engage them.
	Submitting a talk
		Start with the title
			Draw people in
		The audience
			Who will be there?
			How will people decide to see your talk?
			Say what you're going to discuss in detail.
			Specify the audience.
		Some types
			The Case Study
			The Deep Dive
			The Overview
			The “Let Me Show You”
		The abstract
			Style
				Be succinct
				Be specific
				Capture your excitement and passion about the topic in your proposal
				Use inclusive language and avoid shaming
				Show them you’ve been there.
				Check the detail, make it polished
				Show, don’t tell
			Structure
				Put the important facts first.
				Background and introduction.
				Problem statement/thesis.
				Specify the takeaways.
				Stay away from product pitches
				How will you give the audience a superpower?
				Tell a story
		Good bio
			Provide links to your stuff, if you want them to look at it
		Have your proposal reviewed
			Ask friends
			Someone with experience
			Ask for feedback on your proposals
		Submit more than one proposal
